JACOB SHUMAN

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

- **&** (647) 913-5786
- *Ş* jacob-shuman
- @ jacob.shuman7@gmail.com

I am a <u>creative</u> and <u>experienced</u> professional <u>senior-level</u> developer who has worked on projects that are highly **scalable** and **functional**.

An application is only as good as it's interface which is why I am also experienced in designing highly **accessible** and **performant** user interfaces.

□□ Technologies

Languages, Libraries, and Frameworks

JavaScript, Typescript, Java, C++, Dart, Python, React, Nextjs, Remix, Angular, Svelte, Solid, Preact, SQL, Flutter, Ionic, Capacitor, React Native, TailwindCSS

Tools and Services

VSCode, Postman, Visual Studio, Git, GitHub, Firebase, Slack, Heroku, Discord, Supabase AppWrite

Education

Computer Programming and Analysis

Advanced Diploma Seneca College January 2018 - December 2020

Bachelors of Software Development

Bachelors Degree Seneca College January 2021 - Present



Experience

Lab Assistant

Seneca College 2018 - 2019

- Assist students in understanding technical concepts relevant to their current level of programming knowledge.
- Debug student's projects in C and C++.
- Assist students in completing their assignments.

Junior Developer

Smarty Pants 2019 - 2021

- Work with other developers to maintain and build a social media platform for the organization.
- Adapt to new technologies and quickly research and learn how to use them.
- Solve technical issues by collaborating with other team members and researching online.

Senior Developer

Smarty Pants 2021 - Present

- Organized and maintained the technical timeline of tasks for my department.
- Led the development and maintenance of the organization's social media platform.
- Onboard and provide leadership to new junior developers and interns.